Martin Haensch

Menlo Park, CA
✓ Eligibility: Eligible to work in the U.S.
Personal website: https://mhansch.com/

+1 (650) 223-3141 haenschmartin@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/martin-haensch/

SUMMARY

Hi! I am a determined, reliable and dedicated Full Stack Software Developer, equipped with a Bachelor's degree, 5+ years of professional experience, a strong German accent, an unrestricted US work permit, and an unstoppable motivation to make the world a better, safer, and more connected place. I have recently relocated to the Bay Area and am therefore now looking for new professional challenges and development opportunities here.

EDUCATION

University of Applied Sciences Mittelhessen (THM)

Giessen, Germany

10/2014 - 05/2018

Degree: Bachelor of Engineering (Major: Electrical and Information Technology & Automation Engineering)

CERTIFICATES

Algorithms and Data Structures, Web Development, Databases, Front-End Engineer, Design Patterns

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Software Developer

In cooperation with TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

05/2018 - 11/2020

smart.ModoCorrente (http://cloudswitching.de): Cloud-based PLC controlling system (smart home for industrial purposes)

- The idea to develop this product was based on my bachelor thesis. The product development was sponsored by the company TeDatCo GmbH, where I acted as a software engineer and business partner during this time.
- I was responsible for the product from concept to production (front- & backend programming), including the following tasks:
 - Programming a functional PLC (Siemens S7-1200) which connects to an external server (SCL in TIA-Portal)
 - API programming to handle connections between the database and the PLC (C#)
 - Programming a customer friendly website to control PLC outputs (PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
 - Handling database structures (MongoDB) & active documentation of the processes
 - Training and managing new staff with diverse professional backgrounds (e.g., sales).
 - Impact (success parameters): Originally developed for renewable energy facilities, smart. ModoCorrente launched on the German market in 2019 and optimizes maintenance while reducing downtime by up to 100% for customers in various industries. Reported savings from current customers up to 600k Euros.

Utilized: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, AJAX, Bootstrap, PHP, C#, MongoDB, TIA Portal, TCP/IP, Git

Automation Engineer

TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

10/2015 - 04/2018

ModoCorrente (<u>www.modoCorrente.de</u>): System to remote control renewable energy facilities (e.g., wind, solar)

- PLC Programming, Human Machine Interface (WinCC) & configuration of controls networks (e.g., Ethernet, fieldbus)
- Planning and installing control systems for renewable energy components (e.g., wind turbines)
- · Preparing technical drawings and handling circuit diagrams
- Wiring electrical components, mounting control cabinet including on-site troubleshooting, electrical test equipment

Utilized: TIA Portal, SPlan, Network technologies, Antenna technology, GSM, Bus Protocols, Glass fiber technologies, HMI

Data Analyst

Philipps University Marburg, Germany

01/2017 - 01/2018

Preparing and processing physiological data sets for medical research staff

Utilized: Python, MS Excel, VBA, Matlab

Vocational Training / Office Manager

PMCS GmbH & Co. KG, Germany

08/2009 - 06/2012

Military Service (Joint Medical Service) Germa

German Military, Germany

07/2007 - 05/2009

OTHER PROJECTS

"Bartists" (in progress): Platform to connect bars and artists

• Full stack web development project including frontend, backend, and design *Utilized*: *JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, PHP, Laravel, MySQL*

"Plantguard" (smart home application): Controller to water plants automatically

Programming a NodeESP-Board with sensors and actors to water plants automatically
Utilized: Arduino Software, C

SKILLS